CASEY JO FLECK

Davis, CA 95618 ♦ (843)3334527 ♦ CASEJOFLECK@GMAIL.COM LINKEDIN.COM/IN/CASEYJOFLECK ♦ GITHUB.COM/CASEYJOFLECK

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software engineer with 3+ years of experience using agile software development techniques, working with large amounts of data on a granular level, and researching complex coding projects. Proven ability to learn new concepts fast, effectively communicate and collaborate with others. Ambitious, go-getter who can see the big picture and prioritize work to make an impact on the businesses' vision and customers' needs.

SKILLS

- Software Engineering & Development, Programming, Data Analysis, Statistics, Testing, Bug Fixing
- Communication, Leadership, Teamwork, Collaboration, Problem-solving
- Fluent in logical programming languages such as Java, SQL, Maven, Jenkins, SVN, Eclipse, JQuery, JavaScript, and Spring Framework
- Experienced with ArcGIS, ESRI software, Remote Desktop, Linux, Power Bi, C, and MATLAB

WORK HISTORY

Horry Telephone Cooperative Inc. (HTC), – Conway, SC

Software Engineer,09/2017 to Current

- Strategized and planned automatic notifications with HTML and Java 11 EE for service outages which resulted in 56% less customer service and network team cases eliminating the need to hire new customer service employees, with estimated \$45k in savings.
- Reconstructed a tree-like structure list of devices using a dynatree to help the HTC Network Operation Center detect device outages on the network using Java.
- Oversaw the import of more than 5,000 financial reporting records from outdated accounting systems into existing HTC databases with each record having an average \$1500 per material by utilizing Java streams, regular expressions, Java 11 EE, and EntityDao.
- Integrated 5 different API's from various outside applications into one application using web service calls and parsing JSON objects through regular expressions.
- Executed multithreading and Java streams for a batch job that identified and procedurally granted 200 customers bundled discounts saving each customer around \$40 per month.
- Designed and implemented proprietary web applications using Spring Framework, JQuery and JavaScript.
 - o Streamlined search, create, update, and delete operations for employees.

Coastal Carolina University (CCU), - Conway, SC

Computer Science and Mathematics Tutor, 09/2016 to 05/2017

• Mentored students in Java, SQL, Assembly, Statistics and Calculus for various projects and assignments.

Computer IT Technician, 11/2014 to 09/2016

• Assisted students with configuring, troubleshooting and resolving software and network malfunctions.

Washington State University - Pullman, WA, 05/2017 to 08/2017

Re-engineered research-driven search engines to diversify and broaden the range of results implemented with breadth-first search using Java 8 EE library, Maven, SVN, and Neo4j.

EDUCATION

MVC and REST Certification - Conway, SC, 02/2020

 Attended course offered by HTC to learn new techniques and different capabilities within Spring 4, Spring MVC and Spring REST.

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science, Applied Mathematics Minor, 3.88 GPA

Coastal Carolina University, Honors College, Conway, SC - 08/2014 to 12/2018

- **Projects:** Discovered 10 unique permutations that solve the Rubik's Cube from any state in under 20 moves by emulating tree-like structures in C.
- Organizations: Upsilon Pi Epsilon, Pi Mu Epsilon, Women In Computing